{"data":[{"question":"Twelve inches make one ______.","a":"yard","b":"foot","c":"metre","d":"feet","answer":"2","explain":"\n-1 inch = 2.54 centimeters \n-1 foot = 30.48 centimeters ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"How high is this building?' 'It _______'","a":"is 80 metres","b":"is 80 metres high","c":"has 80 metres","d":"has 80 metres high","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Number + unit + high: to express how high something is","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"This race is of three miles. It is ______ race.","a":"a three mile","b":"a three miles","c":"a three-mile","d":"one three-mile","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Compound Adjectives with Numbers: number+ name of thing (in singular) \n- Usually, hyphens are used to link the words together to show that it is one adjective ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Two yards will make ______ feet.","a":"6","b":"12","c":"9","d":"10","answer":"1","explain":"\n-1 yard: 3 feet, or 36 inches (0.9144 meter). ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"In Great Britain petrol is sold _______.","a":"by the gallon","b":"by the litre","c":"in gallons","d":"in litres","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Gallon is unit of petrol in Britain","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"You can now buy beer in _______.","a":"one pint bottles","b":"a pint bottles","c":"one pint bottle","d":"one-pint bottles","answer":"4","explain":"-Compound Adjectives with Numbers: number+ name of thing (in singular)\n\n- Usually, hyphens are used to link the words together to show that it is one adjective\n\n- Gain weight: increase weight","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If one inch is divided into 8 eighths, half an inch is _______.","a":"4 cms","b":"4 eighths","c":"4 knots","d":"4 ounces","answer":"2","explain":"\n- 4 eighths= half of 8 eighths","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If you run a marathon, you run about _______ miles","a":"42","b":"35","c":"26","d":"50","answer":"3","explain":"- A marathon: about 26 miles","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Big Ben _______.","a":"is 98 metres height","b":"has 98 metres of height","c":"has 98 metres","d":"is 98 metres high","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Number + unit + high: to express how high something is ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"A train travelling at 100 miles an hour is doing _______ kilometres an hour.","a":"40","b":"240","c":"160","d":"200","answer":"3","explain":"- 1 mile = 1.609 kilometres","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"71","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"}]}